New Music Edition Compositions
New Music Edition Compositions
1947-1955
New Music Edition.
1.5 linear ft.
Papers of the music publisher. Submitted, but never published, choral and instrumental compositions by 16 composers.
149332
Biographical History
New Music Edition was an imprint of music publisher Carl Fischer LLC. They published both choral and instrumental works.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection of New Music Edition Compositions consists of compositions submitted, but never published. Sixteen composers are represented in the collection, in both choral and instrumental works.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by composer.
Subject and Genre Headings
Music; Ames, W. T.; Archer, Violet.; Brogue, Roslyn, 1919-; Brown, Merton, 1913-2001.; Cuming, Richard.; Engel, Lehman, 1910-1982.; Goodman, Alfred Grant, 1910-; Hurst, George, 1926-2012.; Lavender, William.; Moss, Larry, 1927-; Parris, Robert, 1924-1999.; Ricklis, Leon.; Siracusa, Frank.; Stanley, William P.; Stearns, Peter Pindar.; Watt, Jay.; New Music Edition -- Archives.; Music publishers -- United States.; Composers.; 78 rpm records.; Musical scores.; Composers.; Music publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frank Wigglesworth, 1987.
Inventory
- Compositions
  - Ames, W. T.
    - Sonata for viola and piano, 1952 (Oversize 1)
    - Song cycle, words by Adelaide Crapsey, 1951; November night; Susanna and the elders; The guarded wound; Amaze; The warning (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1951; undated; Meeting; Rapid transit for high voice and piano; Star moss; Pygmalion, by H.D.; Now close the windows (Robert Frost) (Oversize 1)
  - Archer, Violet
    - Divertimento, for oboe, Bb clarinet, and bassoon, undated (Oversize 1)
    - Death be not proud, for male chorus, Feb 1949 (Oversize 1)
  - Brogue, Roslyn
    - Quartet for piano and strings: a fantasy on the chanson, "Mille regretz", 1949 (Oversize 1)
  - Brown, Merton
    - Suite for string quartet, 1950 (Oversize 1)
  - Cumming, Richard
    - Prelude, adagio and toccata (for organ?), 1952 (Oversize 1)
    - The knight's page, for recitation and piano, 1953 (Oversize 1)
    - Piano sonata (published by J&W Chester, London), circa 1953 (Oversize 1)
  - Engel, Lehmann
    - Sonata for violin and piano, 1953; includes photodopy of music with hand corrections, plus test pressing of recorded performance on 2 78rpm phonodiscs (Oversize 1)
  - Goodman, Alfred Grant
    - Seven sketches for piano, op. 16, 1950 (Oversize 1)
  - Hurst, George
    - Fantasy on an original theme, for pianoforte, undated (Oversize 1)
    - Three murders, for baritone and piano, poems by Lawrence Josephs, undated; includes only no. 1, "For Love" (Oversize 1)
  - Lavender, William
    - Toccatina for piano, 1948 (Oversize 1)
    - Monotone, for a cappella chorus, text from Chicago Poems by Carl Sandburg, 1949 (Oversize 1)
    - Fantasy for string orchestra, 1951 (Oversize 1)
  - Moss, Larry
    - Intermezzo, for piano, 1949 (Oversize 1)
    - Four songs on text of Carl Sandburg, for baritone or mezzo-soprano and piano, 1950; Prairie; Fog; Village in late summer; Autumn movement (Oversize 1)
    - Elegy, for piano, 1949 (Oversize 1)
  - Parris, Robert
    - Three love lyrics, for tenor and piano, undated; Madrigal (anon.); Eyes, hide my love (Daniel); Madrigal (Wilbye) (Oversize 1)
    - Three songs from The Gardener (Rabindranath Tagore), for baritone with the accompaniment of piano and celesta, 1948 (Oversize 1)
    - In time like grass, for voice and piano, 1949 (Oversize 1)
  - Ricklis, Leon
    - Fantasy sextet, for string quartet, percussion and piano, 1950 (Oversize 1)
  - Siracusa, Frank
    - Three studies for keyboard, 1954 (Oversize 1)
    - Chant for keyboard, 1953 (Oversize 1)
    - Concert for a chamber trio, flute, Bb trumpet and viola, 1953 (Oversize 1)
    - Chamber quartet, for Bb clarinet, tenor trombone, cello, piano, 1954 (Oversize 1)
  - Stanley, William P.
    - Three songs from The Tower, by William Butler Yeats, undated; The fool by the roadside; from Sailing to Byzantium; A prayer for my son (Oversize 1)
    - Sonata for cello and piano, undated (Oversize 1)
  - Stearns, Peter Pindar
    - Four lyrics from The Book of Tao (Lao Tse), for soprano and clarinet, 1954 (Oversize 1)
    - Sonata for piano, 1954 (Oversize 1)
    - String quartet no. 3 in A minor, 1955 (Oversize 1)
  - Watt, Jay
    - Prelude [for piano], 1951 (Oversize 1)